Irving Lehman Papers
Irving Lehman Papers
1935-1973
Lehman, Irving, 1900-1983.
0.25 linear ft.
Papers of the American Jewish painter, sculptor, engraver, designer. Born in Russia. Photographs of Lehman's paintings and sculpture (1935-1963); clippings (1958-1961); and exhibition catalogs, invitations, and posters (1947-1960).
149755
Biographical History
Irving Lehman (1900-1983) was an American Jewish painter, sculptor, engraver, and designer. Born in Kiev in Russia, Lehman studied at Cooper Union and the National Academy of Art and spent much of his working life in New York City. Part of the Abstract Expressionist school, he worked in oil and watercolor as a painter and in metal and steel as a sculptor; his works have been shown in galleries in England, France, Italy, Israel and Japan, and were included in an international traveling exhibition in Europe in 1951.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
Spanning 1935 to 1973, the Irving Lehman Papers comprises artwork reproductions and memorabilia.
Artwork (reproductions) consists of three personal greeting cards incorporating photographs of Lehman's artwork, and photographs of his paintings and sculpture. Memorabilia includes a photograph of Lehman with one of his sculptures, and some printed material: three newspaper clippings about Lehman, exhibition catalogs and invitations, and two exhibition posters.
Arrangement of the Collection
Reproductions are arranged alphabetically by title of work. Memorabilia is arranged alphabetically by type.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Painters; Art -- Sculptors; Lehman, Irving, 1900-1983 -- Archives.; Art, American.; Art, American -- 20th century.; Jewish artists -- United States.; Jews, American.; Painters -- United States.; Painting, American.; Painting, American -- 20th century.; Russian Americans.; Sculptors -- United States.; Sculpture, American.; Sculpture, American -- 20th century.; Clippings (information artifacts); Exhibition catalogs.; Photographs.; Artists.; Painters.; Sculptors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Artwork (reproductions)
  - Greeting cards (personal), 1964; 1971,; undated (Box 1)
  - Photographs
    - Paintings (by title), A-Z (Box 1)
    - Sculpture (by title), A-Z (Box 1)
- Memorabilia
  - Photograph, Irving Lehman with "Machinist" sculpture, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Printed material
    - Clippings, 1958; 1961 (Box 1)
    - Exhibition catalogs, invitations, 1947-1964; 1973,; undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Exhibition posters, 1959; 1960 (Box 1)